Subindex build by Linnet
http://linnet.126.com  http://blog.csdn.net/redbirdli
火鸟字幕合并器SubindexV0.5
Created time 11.10.31 10:53:30
-=The Last Fantasy=-
这个值多少钱？
How much will you give me for it?
50块
Fifty bucks.
是金子做的哎
It's made out of gold.
- 谁告诉你的？ - 我老妈
-Who told you that? -My mother.
告诉她这是假的
Tell her it's a fake.
没法告诉她了
I can't.
她死掉了
She's dead.
那我给你60块吧
I'll give you sixty bucks.
怎么样了？
So, what's the deal?
- 我告诉过你们我不想做这种事了 - 我们这是最后一次了
-I told you, I don't want to do this anymore. -Oh, this is our last job.
骗人
Liar.
小孩！你现在只能靠我们
We're all you've got, kid.
告诉我他的密码
Tell me the combination.
45-13-29
25-13-29.
这才是好孩子
Good boy.
好了，你们知道该怎么做吧？
Okay, you know the drill, right?
- 我们开始吧 - 拿上包，我们开始了
-Let's do this. -Get the bag. Let's go.
不要忘记我的天使
Don't forget my angel.
怎么了？ 你们是什么人？
What's going on here? Hey, who are you people?
噢,我的天啊，不要！不要！
Oh, my God, no! No!
天哪！他死掉了！
Oh, my God, I think he's dead.
- 快走！ - 你为什么要这样做?
-Let's go! -No. What did you do that for?
不是他死就是我们亡，宝贝，我们快走！
It was him or us, baby. We gotta go!
快点
Come on.
他要去那里？追啊
Where's he going? Go.
赖恩！
Ryan!
我的天哪
Oh, my God.
你还好吧？
Are you all right?
- 你还好吗？ - 我鞋子掉了
-Are you all right? -I lost my shoe.
我要带你去医院！快，起来
I'm taking you to the hospital. Come on.
片名:超人前传
主题曲《Save me》:谁来拯救我
领衔主演：汤姆・威灵
让你温暖的手伸出驱散我的痛苦
主演:克丽斯汀・克鲁克
谁来拯救我
主演:迈克尔・罗森巴姆
我不在乎你是怎么做到
主演：埃里克・约翰森
只要你留下，和我在一起
主演：山姆・琼斯三世
快来吧，我一直在等待着你
主演：艾利森・麦克
主演：安妮特・奥图尔
约翰・施耐得 饰演 强纳森・肯特
我一直留着整个世界只为你闪耀
超人始创作者:杰瑞・希杰尔和乔・夏斯特
留下，留下
快出现吧
电视策划:阿尔弗雷德・哥夫，麦尔斯・米莱
第十六集:孤儿
他的身体没有大碍 只是一些淤青和划伤
He checks out physically, just scrapes and bruises.
和他的父母联系过了吗？
Have you managed to contact his parents yet?
除了名字以外 赖恩说他什么都不记得了
Other than knowing his name, Ryan claims to have no memory.
特别客串主演:约翰・格鲁夫
Are you saying he has amnesia?
True amnesia is extremely rare. It's most likely post-traumatic shock.
客串主演:赖安・科利
His memory will probably return within 24 to 48 hours.
What if it doesn't?
Martha, Jonathan.
吉姆・希尔德
布兰迪・雷德佛
It's unlikely all Ryan's cuts and bruises were caused by the accident.
-You think he's been abused? -He may not want to remember.
联合执行制片:格列哥・比曼
What will happen to him?
监督制片:马克・伏黑顿
We've called Child Services, but they're understaffed...
...and can't come until tomorrow at the earliest.
So the only place for Ryan to stay is at the juvenile cell at the sheriff's station.
-That's no place for a child. -Why can't he come home with us?
-That's a great idea. -Can we do that?
制片人:迈克尔・格林
I'll have to make some calls, but I don't see why not.
It'd be a big help to us, and I'm sure Ryan would appreciate it.
制片人:道里斯・伊根
-Clark? -It's me, Mrs. Kent.
-Ryan, did you do all this? -I hope you don't mind. I couldn't sleep.
联合制片:格雷格・沃克
-Hey, what's the occasion? -I wanted to make myself useful.
-Thanks for letting me stay here. -Stay as long as you want.
制片人:鲍勃・哈格罗夫
Maybe some of you will rub off on Clark.
What does everybody want? Let me guess...
...pancakes...
...with powdered sugar...
...not syrup.
-How did you know that? -I saw you eyeing them when you came in.
Scrambled eggs...
...bacon...
联合执行制片:肯・霍顿
...coffee with milk and a little bit of honey.
编剧:菲利普・莱温斯
Well, that is some trick there, kiddo.
导演:保罗・沙尔皮罗
你是说他失忆了？
真正的失忆是很少见的 更像是受刺激导致的创伤后应激障碍
他的记忆大概在24到48小时之内就会恢复
如果没有呢？
玛莎，强纳森
莱恩身上淤青和伤口 不完全是车祸造成的
- 你觉得他受过虐待？ - 他可能不愿意想起来
那打算以后怎么安排他这事？
我们给儿童中心打过电话了， 但是他们的人手不够...
...最早明早才能到
所以今晚赖恩只能去少管所了
- 那不是小孩子该呆的地方 - 我们为什么不能把他带回家呢？
- 这是个好主意 - 我们可以带他回去么？
我需要打几个电话确认下 不过应该没什么问题的
真是帮了我们大忙 我相信赖恩会很感激的
- 克拉克？ - 是我，肯特夫人
- 这些都是你做的吗？ - 希望你不会介意，我睡不着
- 这是要庆祝什么？ - 我希望自己能派上用场
- 谢谢你们让我待在这 - 你想待多久就多久
说不定能给克拉克带来好影响
大家都想吃什么？让我来猜下…
煎饼
加糖末
…但不加糖浆…
- 你是怎么知道的？ - 你一进来的时候就盯着它们
炒蛋…
…熏肉…
…咖啡加牛奶和一点点的蜂蜜
- 噢，真是奇妙的把戏，孩纸
- 嗨，妈 - 嗨
-Hey, Mom. -Hi.
给新小孩做了大餐啊
Going all out for the new kid, huh?
其实啊，克拉克 都是赖恩自己做的
Actually, Clark, Ryan took care of all this himself.
让我情何以堪啊
You're making me look bad.
你早餐想吃点什么？
What do you want for breakfast?
- 克拉克，你什么都不想吃么？ - 我要煎饼就好了
-Don't you want anything, Clark? -I'm just gonna have some pancakes.
赖恩，你没事吧？
Ryan, you okay?
赖恩，你真的不记得昨晚的事了吗？
Ryan, are you sure you don't remember anything about last night?
其实，我还是没搞明白...
You see, because I still can't figure out...
…为什么晚上10点，你会在90号高速上
...why you were out on Route 90 at 10:00 at night.
我说过我不记得了
I said I don't remember.
我什么都没隐瞒
I'm not hiding anything.
没人说你隐瞒了，孩子
No one said you were, buddy.
翻译:pooh,皮皮，哈拉尔，Herbalmin，龙猫 校对:岁月倒影，TYY
我猜你父母现在想让我离开了
Guess your parents want me to leave now.
- 你为什么这么想？ - 因为他们不相信我
-Why would you think that? -Because they don't believe me.
- 我们只是想帮你回家 - 如果我没有家呢？
-We just want to help you get home. -What if I don't have a home?
如果你们知道我做过坏事，会怎样呢？
What if you found out I did bad things? What would happen?
相信我，赖恩，一切都会好起来的
Ryan, everything's gonna work out. I know it.
你喜欢看漫画？
You like comics?
我很喜欢这一套
I like this one.
《战斗天使》，为什么喜欢他？
Warrior Angel. Why him?
因为他保护那些保护不了自己的人
Because he protects people who can't protect themselves.
克拉克，我喜欢待在你身边
I like being around you, Clark.
觉得很安心
It's peaceful.
为什么不放下漫画书，来打会儿球呢？
Why don't you get your head out of that comic and play a little ball?
- 你一定觉得我很差劲 - 没关系，多练练就好了
-I know what you're thinking. I really suck. -Nothing a little practice can't cure.
来吧，抬起你的手臂，手肘保持竖直
Go ahead. Get your hand up, keep your elbows straight...
让球顺着你的手指导出去
...just guide the ball with your fingers.
- 哇！你投中加分了！ - 是啊！
-He shoots, and he scores! -Yeah.
太棒了！
Nice.
打扰一下
Excuse me.
- 怎么？ - 我在找告示上的那个男孩
-Yes. -I'm looking for the boy from the paper.
就是那个失忆的那个
You know, the one who lost his memory.
- 你是？ - 私家侦探
-And you are? -A private detective.
我帮一对夫妇在找他们走失的儿子
I work for a couple who lost their son.
赖恩还在这里吗？
Is Ryan still around?
没有…
No...
…麻烦你等一下 我帮你叫一下哈登医生，她会跟你详谈
...but if you just wait, I'll get Dr. Harden. I know she'd like to speak with you.
真棒！
All right.
很和谐，是吧？
That's a great sound, isn't it?
是啊
Yeah, it is.
你有没有想再领养一个孩子？
Do you ever think we made the wrong decision, not adopting another child?
或许有个可以分享秘密的弟弟 会让他感觉更舒服
Maybe sharing his secret with a younger brother would have helped.
他看上去确实很喜欢赖恩
He seems to really like Ryan.
大家都很喜欢赖恩啊
I don't think he's the only one.
- 你对无家可归的小孩总是没有抵抗力 - 事实证明我们收养克拉克是明智的
-You've always had a soft spot for strays. -Well, the last one turned out all right.
来吧，再来一次
Here you go. One more.
哇！太棒了！
Oh, nice.
我以为你还在摩纳哥呢
I thought you were still in Monaco.
"惊喜的精髓就在于速度和保密"
"The backbone of surprise is fusing speed with secrecy."
出自卡尔・冯・克劳塞维茨的《战争论》
Von Clausevitz, On War.
爸爸，即使是对于你来说，这本书也太古老了吧
Isn't that a little '80s, Dad, even for you?
我去检查工厂从来不通知经理
I never give my plant managers a heads-up before a spot inspection.
我真不知道你现在还有什么不满意的？
What could you possibly have to complain about now?
工厂的生意不错，股价也在持续上涨…
The plant's doing well, LuthorCorp stock is up....
莱克斯，我没有什么不满意的
I'm not here to complain, Lex.
相反，我觉得你最近的表现…
On the contrary. Your performance lately has been...
…让我相当满意
...more than adequate.
这赞赏听上去还别有深意吧
That sounds dangerously like a compliment.
莱克斯，我不否认 我拿更大的期望在督促你
I push you, Lex, I don't deny it.
伟大是一种稀薄的空气 我必须教你如何去呼吸
Greatness is a rarefied air one has to be taught to breathe.
马其顿将儿子在狮群中喂养 就是为了教会他勇敢无畏
Philip of Macedonia raised his son among lions to instill fearlessness in him.
他也试过用长矛刺穿儿子吗？
Didn't he also try to impale the kid with a spear?
在一次失败的政变中他试过
In an aborted coup attempt...
但重要的是那个男孩青史留名 他就是亚历山大大帝
...but history remembers that boy as Alexander the Great.
你来这不是为了教我希腊历史吧
You didn't come all this way to lecture me on Greek history.
不，我想叫你回大都会
No. I want you to come back to Metropolis...
我让你担任"名誉主席特别顾问"的职位
...where you will hold the position "special advisor to the chairman emeritus."
也就是我的顾问
That would be me.
- 至少这个头衔听上去很有份量 - 它不仅仅是个头衔，更是一次机会
-At least the title sounds important. -It's more than a title. It's an opportunity.
也正是你来斯摩维尔所苦苦等待的机会
It's what you've been waiting for ever since you came to Smallville.
我会考虑一下的
I'll think about it.
你现在吊我胃口 弄得像是你帮我的忙一样
You want to keep me dangling, so it looks like you're granting me a favor...
而并不是我帮你的忙
...instead of receiving one?
儿子，你没必要和我耍心机
We don't need to play games, son.
爸爸，我们除了耍心机还剩什么
Dad, games are all we've got.
- 哇，你真是现代的卡斯帕・豪瑟啊 - 他是谁？
-Wow, you're a modern-day Kaspar Hauser. -Who's that?
别管了，克罗伊总是很擅长 说一些我们听不懂的东西
Don't worry. Chloe's the queen of obscure and irrelevant references.
他是19世纪一个失忆的男孩
He's a kid from the 19th century with amnesia.
他出现一个德国小镇，不记得自己是谁
He showed up in a German town without a memory of who he was...
只记得自己的名字
...all he could remember was his name.
- 后来怎么样了？ - 他的故事被传播到整个欧洲
-What happened to him? -Well, his story spread throughout Europe...
各地的人都赶来看他是不是自己走失的孩子
...and people from all over came to see if he was their missing child.
有些人认为他是大公爵的那个走失的孩子
Some people thought he was the lost son of the grand duke.
- 后来他找到父母了吗？ - 是这样的…
-Did he ever find his parents? -You know....
是的，找到了
Yeah, he did.
他找到了父母 从此一家人幸福地生活在一起
He found his parents, and they lived happily ever after.
你为什么不直接说他被谋杀了？
Why didn't you just say he was murdered?
你怎么会知道呢？
How did you know that?
好吧，我们为什么不照张相呢
You know, why don't we take that picture?
照什么相啊？
What picture?
你不是要把我放在那个变态墙上展示吧？
You're not putting me on that freak wall, are you?
那个墙叫“怪异之墙”，而且我并不是要放你上去
It's called the Wall of Weird, and no...
这张照片只是为了核对失踪的人
...this picture is just to check against missing persons.
好了，我去把照片冲印出来，一会儿就好
Okay, I'm gonna go download this. I'll be there in a sec.
- 她喜欢你 - 当然，我们是朋友
-She likes you. -Yeah, we're friends.
她不仅仅想和你做朋友
She wants to be more than just friends.
- 她希望你能邀请她去舞会 - 克罗伊吗？
-She wants you to ask her to the prom. -Chloe?
- 好吧，你是对的 - 肯定是的
-Yeah, right. -No, really.
她已经挑好了裙子，是粉色的
She already picked out a dress. It's pink.
赖恩，你才刚认识克罗伊 而且她讨厌穿裙子
Ryan, you just met Chloe, and she hates dresses...
并且她也不是那种喜欢去舞会的人
...and she's not exactly the prom type.
也许她有你不知道的浪漫一面呢
Maybe she has a romantic side you never knew about.
或者也许我妈妈把你的脑子撞坏了
Or maybe my mom hit you harder than I thought.
让我再给你们两个拍一张
Let's get a picture of my boys.
你觉得有个小弟弟感觉怎么样？
So how does it feel having a little-brother-type figure in your life?
- 感觉不错 - 我一直希望能有一个兄弟姐妹
-It's pretty cool. -I dreamed of having a brother or sister...
能在无聊的时候一起聊聊天
...someone to talk to, help fill the silence.
能一直陪在你身边 让你可以绝对信任的人？
Someone you can totally trust and would always be there for you.
克拉克，你在我心中就是这样的
That's just how I see you, Clark.
谢谢
Thanks.
《战斗天使》，我很喜欢它
Warrior Angel. I'm a fan myself.
- 你一定是赖恩吧，我是… - 莱克斯・卢瑟
-You must be Ryan. I'm-- -Lex Luthor.
克拉克早和我谈过你了
Clark told me all about you.
- 我家里有一本… - 装框的珍藏首版
-You know, I have one of the-- -First-edition panels framed in your house.
- 你怎么会知道？ - 你是富豪啊，猜到了
-How did you know that? -You're rich.
富豪们总是喜欢收藏
That's what rich people do, collect stuff.
我看你见过赖恩了
I see you've met Ryan.
明显我们都是《战斗天使》的死忠粉丝
Apparently, we're both big Warrior Angel fans.
我都不知道你喜欢漫画书
I didn't know you liked comic books.
从另一个星球来的访客想保护弱小？
A strange visitor from another planet who protects the weak?
我小的时候，他是我的偶像 更别提他也是个秃头了
When I was young, he was my idol, not to mention he's bald.
我有全套收藏
I have the whole collection.
- 我们可以晚点过去看看 - 好的
-Maybe we'll come by later and check it out. -Yeah.
- 你觉得怎么样，老弟？ - 随便
-Would you like that, buddy? -Whatever.
随便
Whatever.
这样有点粗鲁
That was kind of rude.
- 莱克斯是我的朋友 - 别担心他，他快离开小镇了
-Lex is my friend. -Don't worry about him. He's going to leave.
莱克斯的爸爸给他找了个新工作
Lex's father offered him a new job.
你不了解莱克斯的爸爸 他绝不会这么做
You don't know Lex's father. He would never do that.
你必须停止编造别人的故事
You have to stop making up stories about people.
过会见
I'll see you in a minute.
赖恩？
Ryan?
赖恩刚从后门逃走了 他看起来很害怕，克拉克
Ryan just took off out the back. He looked scared, Clark.
赖恩？
Ryan?
救命
Help!
你现在安全了
You're safe now.
克拉克，你的小跟班呢
Clark, where's your young sidekick?
睡觉呢
Sleeping.
他觉得你是他的大哥哥
He thinks you're his big brother.
恩，我猜也是，但到明天为止
Yeah, well, I guess I am, till tomorrow.
- 你越来越喜欢那孩子了 - 你知道的
-The kid is growing on you. -You know how it is.
作为独生子，没人在身边
Being an only child, no one else around.
你难道从没想过有个兄弟姐妹吗
Don't you ever wish you had a sibling?
我曾经有过一个，克拉克
I had one, Clark.
真的吗？我都不知道
Really? I didn't know.
当我11岁的时候，我妈又怀孕了
When I was 11, my mother got pregnant again.
这是个奇迹，我从没见我父亲能比这更开心
It was a total surprise. I've never seen my father happier.
朱利安出生的那天是唯一的一次...
The day Julian was born was the only time...
...我感觉我的家庭有人情味
...I felt like I was part of a real family.
然后怎么了
And what happened?
他洗礼的那个早晨，我妈去育婴室...
The morning of his baptism, my mother went to his nursery...
...发现他在婴儿床上，已经断气了
...found him in his crib, he had stopped breathing.
在那以后，我母亲变了个性情 我父亲也变得更冷漠
My mother was never the same after that, and my father got even more distant.
他把朱利安看作是第二次机会
I think he saw Julian as his second chance.
一次他能好好爱儿子的机会
A chance for him to have a son he could truly love.
对不起
I'm sorry.
都已经过去了，克拉克
It's in the past, Clark.
不管怎样，我跟他最后都会讨厌对方
We would have ended up hating each other, anyway.
我父亲肯定会想法设法做到跟我互相仇恨的
My father would have seen to that.
但我来这里不是为了说我家的悲剧的
But I didn't come over to recount my family's tragic history.
我父亲给我一个重回大都会的机会
My father has offered me a chance to return to Metropolis.
你告诉过赖恩吗?
Did you tell Ryan about that?
我还没告诉任何人，克拉克
I haven't told anyone, Clark.
这不正是你一直想要的
Well, that's what you always wanted.
我曾经是这么想
I used to think it was.
但现在不确定了
Now I'm not so sure.
我在那就是另一个人了
I was a different person there.
我父亲身边不同的人
A different person around my father.
他明晚就要答案，我们会去大都会晚餐
He wants an answer tomorrow night. We're having dinner in Metropolis.
如果有人可以 选择成为什么样的人，莱克斯...
If anyone can choose who they want to be, Lex...
...那必定是你
...it's you.
- 敲门了 - 肯特先生，真意外
-Knock, knock. -Mr. Kent, this is a surprise.
赖恩跟我干了一整天的活，他应该休息下
Yeah, Ryan's been doing chores with me all day, so I figured he deserved a break.
我想要一杯咖啡，给他点他想要的...
I'd like a cup of coffee, give him whatever he wants...
...告诉我电话在哪，我去问问玛莎要什么
...and if you can point me to a phone, I'll see if Martha wants anything.
- 好的，在后面 - 好的，玩得开心点
-All right, it's in the back. -All right. Enjoy.
- 今天感觉怎么样? - 好多了，谢谢
-So how you feeling today? -Much better, thanks.
很好
Good.
你觉得朋友间有秘密好不好
Do you think it's okay if friends have secrets?
奇怪的问题，你怎么这么问？
Strange question. Why do you ask?
因为我觉得克拉克向我隐瞒了一些事
Because I think Clark is hiding something from me.
每个人都有秘密，赖恩
Everybody has secrets, Ryan.
真的吗？你的呢
Really? What's yours?
如果我告诉你，它就不是秘密了
If I told you, then it wouldn't be a secret.
你是对的
I guess you're right.
- 谢谢，斯凯，你来得真及时 - 不用谢
-Thanks, Skye, you're a lifesaver. -You're welcome.
- 为什么皱眉 - 她不是个好人，拉娜
-Why the frown? -She's not a good person, Lana.
你应该解雇他
You should fire her.
赖恩，为什么这么说
Ryan, why would you say something like that?
因为这是事实
Because it's the truth.
你从何得知
How do you know?
这是个秘密
It's a secret.
谢谢你的热巧克力，肯特先生
Thanks for the hot chocolate, Mr. Kent.
看看赖恩，他自己找到了一个新家庭
Looks like Ryan has found himself a new family.
- 该回去工作了 - 什么时候去抓那个孩子
-It's time to get back to work. -When do we get the kid?
一切准备就绪的时候
When we're ready.
我母亲在这附近撞到了他
My mom hit him somewhere around here.
谢谢你帮我搜索线索
Thanks for helping with the clue hunt.
顺便解开赖恩的谜团，我很荣幸
And help solve the riddle of Ryan? It's my pleasure.
这的确是个谜
There really is a riddle.
我开始怀疑他并没有失忆
I'm starting to think he may not have amnesia.
克拉克，那孩子很崇拜你，他为什么要撒谎
Clark, the kid adores you, why would he lie?
因为他在逃避某些人
Because he's running from somebody.
我发现一个包
I found something.
里面有漫画书
We got comic books...
...糖果
...and Twizzlers.
一些成长中的男孩必备品
Something every growing boy needs.
怎么了？我平时藏东西也藏这
What? It's where I would hide something.
如果你是个CIA特工
If you were a CIA operative.
你觉得她会是谁
Who do you think it is?
我不知道....妈妈？阿姨
I don't know.... Mom, aunt?
谜团变深了
And the mystery deepens.
我始终不明白他怎么知道卡斯帕豪瑟被谋杀了
I still can't figure out how he knew that Kaspar Hauser was murdered.
你说谎时脸色那么不自然啊
Well, you weren't exactly wearing a poker face.
赖恩说了一些奇怪的事情
Ryan does say weird things.
他甚至说你想让我请你去参加舞会 而且你还买了条裙子
He even said that you wanted me to ask you to prom and that you'd bought a dress.
不是粉色的吧？
It's not pink, is it?
这个，你知道，我只是看看 没想真买
Okay, you know, I was just looking at it, it's not like I actually bought it.
赖恩怎么知道的？
How would Ryan know that?
我不知道，也许他是个外星人 或者他问了灵媒，总之我也说不清
I don't know. Maybe he's an alien, or maybe he called Miss Cleo. You know, I don't know.
克拉克是你生命中最好的礼物，对吗？
Clark's the best thing that ever happened to you.
你说的对
Yeah, he is.
他弥补了你不能生育的遗憾
He makes up for not being able to have your own kids.
是的
He does.
- 他一直都这么强壮吗？ - 什么意思？
-Has he always been so strong? -What do you mean?
他撕开垃圾车的后板救了我
The way he tore off the back panel of the garbage truck and saved me.
傻瓜，他不可能做到的
Don't be silly, he couldn't do that.
如果你这么说的话…
If you say so.
你最害怕什么？
What's your greatest fear?
在你离开前做不完这个派
That I won't get this pie done by the time you have to leave.
为什么不出去投几个篮玩玩呢？
Why don't you go outside and shoot some hoops?
- 你在这里干什么？ - 克拉克，别生气
-What are you doing down here? -Clark, don't be mad.
你怎么知道这里的？
How'd you know about this?
从你妈妈的思想里读出来的
I heard about it in your mom's mind.
我想亲眼看一看
I wanted to see it for myself.
你可以读出每个人的想法吗？
Can you hear everything people think?
仅限表面的想法
Only what's on the surface.
他们当时当刻的想法
What they're thinking at that moment.
除了你
Except for you.
我读不出你的 所以我认为你很特别
I can't read your mind. That's how I knew you were different.
现在我知道为什么了
Now I know why.
我无法相信你竟然这么做
I can't believe you'd do this.
我不会告诉别人的 你为我保守秘密，我就保守你的
I'll never tell. You keep my secret, I'll keep yours.
- 没那么简单 - 就这么简单
-It's not that simple. -Sure it is.
我知道你爸爸担心别人会发现
I know your dad's worried that people are going to find out.
我可以告诉他有人快要发现了
I can tell him when someone's getting close.
我告诉你克洛伊的秘密 也可以说出拉娜的
I told you about Chloe. I can tell you about Lana.
- 你想知道她的秘密吗？ - 不想
-You want to know her secret? -No.
赖恩，我一点都不想
No, Ryan, I don't.
为什么不呢？
Why not?
是关于你的
It's about you.
你不能这么做
Look, you can't do this.
你不理解和别人不同是什么感觉
You don't understand what it's like to be different.
必须隐藏起来 别人才不会认为你是个怪胎
What it's like to have to hide so people won't think you're a freak.
不管我去哪…
Everywhere I go...
都可以读出别人的想法
...I hear people's thoughts.
我再也不能封闭它
I can't block it out anymore.
这是你妈妈？
Is this your mother?
她死了
She died.
你为什么不告诉我？
Why didn't you tell me?
我希望能在你们家重新开始
I was hoping I could start over with your family.
他们那么善良 我希望他们能像收养你一样收养我
They were so nice. I wanted them to adopt me like they did you.
那我就能安全了
So I'd be safe.
- 谁在追你？ - 我继父和他新妻
-Who's chasing you? -My stepfather and his new wife.
他们一直在利用我
They've been using me.
我的超能力
My abilities.
去偷东西
To steal.
我想停手不干…
I wanted to stop...
…但是他们威胁我
...but they threatened me.
打我
They hit me.
你必须保护我，克拉克 只有你能办到
You have to protect me, Clark. You're the only one that can.
我来开
I'll get it.
你敢说任何事，我就杀了他们
You say anything, and I'll kill them.
你知道我会的
You know I will.
- 你一定是赖恩吧 - 有什么事吗？
-So you must be Ryan. -Can I help you?
肯特先生，儿童保护协会 我来这接赖恩
Mr. Kent, Child Services. I'm here to pick up Ryan.
你来早了 我们本以为你一小时后才来
You're early. We weren't expecting you for an hour.
你们能照顾赖恩，我们很感激
We can't thank you enough for taking Ryan in.
没关系 我们很希望他能呆久些
It's our pleasure. He's welcome to stay longer.
这恐怕不行，我要送他去看护中心
Oh, I'm afraid that's impossible. I need to put him in foster care.
这是法律规定
That's the law.
我们去整理你的东西
Let's get your stuff.
我们认为莱恩可能在逃避他的继父 所以我们知会了警方
We think Ryan might be running away from his stepfather, so we alerted the police.
别担心，我们会保证他的安全 准备好了吗？
Don't worry, we'll keep him safe. Ready to go?
他可以等等跟我们儿子克拉克道别吗？ 他马上就回来
Could he wait and say goodbye to our son, Clark? He'll be home any minute.
抱歉
Oh, I'm sorry.
没关系，肯特夫人
It's okay, Mrs. Kent.
替我跟他道谢
Just tell him thanks.
如果需要什么，打电话给我们，好吗？
If you need anything, just call us, okay?
爸爸，怎么了？
Dad, what's wrong?
儿童保护协会的人15分钟前 来把赖恩接走了
Child Services came and took Ryan away about 15 minutes ago.
啊？
What?
他为什么不等我？ 我想跟他道别
Why didn't he wait for me? I wanted to say goodbye.
我不清楚，孩子…
I don't know, son...
…他们说急着走，抱歉
...they said they were in a hurry. I'm sorry.
准备去大都会
On your way to Metropolis.
是啊，为了大餐
Yeah, for the big dinner.
我…
I....
我想给你个东西
I wanted you to have something.
- 一把剑？ - 是花剑，每个英雄都应该有一把
-A sword? -It's a foil. Every hero should have one.
我猜这意味着你决定离开了
I guess this means you've decided you're leaving.
我还没做出最后决定
I haven't made up my mind one way or the other.
如果还没决定 为什么送我离别礼？
If you haven't made up your mind, why are you giving me a going-away present?
把剑离那个小孩远一点
Keep that away from the kid.
- 他已经走了 - 我很遗憾
-He's already gone. -I'm sorry.
我知道你很喜欢他
I know how much you liked him.
为了弥补，我希望你能留下来
For what it's worth, I hope you stay.
司机？嘿，怎么了？
Driver? Hey, what's going on?
司机？
Driver?
- 进去，快点！ - 你们干什么？
-Inside, come on! -What are you doing?
进去
Get in.
卢瑟先生
Mr. Luthor.
- 赖恩？ - 闭嘴
-Ryan? -Shut up.
好了，走，走
Okay, go. Go.
弄到你的信托基金账号太容易了…
Getting the account number to your trust fund was easy...
…现在给我密码
...now give me the password.
- 我不知道你在说什么 - 快告诉我密码是什么，富家子
-I don't know what you're talking about. -Tell me what it is.
我爸才知道，我不知道
My father has it, I don't.
他在撒谎
He's lying.
密码，马上给我
Password. Now.
你知道了？
You got it?
- 嘿，佐罗，拿剑干什么呢？ - 是花剑
-Hey, Zorro, what's with the sword? -It's a foil.
我猜这是从我们最爱的 百万富翁花花公子那来的礼物
I'm guessing it's a gift from our favorite millionaire playboy.
他在考虑要搬回大都会
He's thinking of moving back to Metropolis.
嗯，我还在这，克拉克 我哪也不会去
Well, I'm still here, Clark. I'm not going anywhere.
警长办公室的消息 给了我关于赖恩继父的警告
Sources at the sheriff's office have given me a heads-up on Ryan's stepdad.
- 你在那有门路 - 对啊，交通司里的一个可爱职员
-You have sources. -Yeah, a cute officer in Traffic.
我费劲口舌逃掉了一张超速罚单 他说我很有勇气
I talked my way out of a speeding ticket, he told me I was plucky.
也许我该邀请他参加舞会
Maybe I'll ask him to prom.
赖恩的继父来头不小 他是职业罪犯
So Ryan's stepdad is a real catch. He's a career criminal.
这是莱克斯座驾的司机
This is Lex's limo driver.
告诉我密码
Give me the password.
别让我再问一遍
Don't make me ask again.
密码是"朱利安"
It's "Julian."
- 莱克斯，你还好吧？ - 应该还行吧
-Lex, are you okay? -Yeah, I think so.
他们去哪了？
Which way did they go?
沿90公路直走 克拉克，他们带着赖恩，赶快求助
Straight down Route 90. Clark, they've got Ryan. Get some help.
出来，烧了这豪车，宝贝儿！
Get out. Torch the limo, baby!
朱利安，朱利安
Julian. Julian.
给我真正的密码，别惹我
Give me the real password. Don't mess with me.
- 我不会告诉你！ - 我向上帝发誓，我现在就毙了他
-I'm not gonna tell you! -I swear to God, I'll drop him right now.
一旦他拿到了钱，他就会杀了你
Once he gets the money, he's gonna kill you.
别听他说，他在挑拨，好把我们分开
Don't listen to him. He's talking trash to pull us apart.
我们的钱就要到手了，宝贝 我们要做的就是彼此信任
We're just about to hit the jackpot, baby. All we've gotta do is trust each other.
你知道的，虽然这孩子总让我生气…
You know, this kid has always freaked me out...
…但我还是会说他从不说谎
...but the one thing I'll say about him is he never lied.
你知道么？
You know what?!
是真的…
That's true...
…他没有说谎
...he didn't.
赖恩！
Ryan!
- 小家伙，你在干什么？ - 叫警察！
-Hey, kid, where are you going? -Call the police!
赖恩！
Ryan!
躲得了一时躲不了一世
You can't hide forever.
你知道，你妈真的恨死你了
You know, your mother really hated you.
她不能容忍生了个怪胎
Couldn't stand having a freak for a son.
想想吧，如果不是那样 我也不会那样对你着迷
Come to think of it, I wasn't that crazy about you either.
- 克拉克！ - 没事了，孩子
-Clark! -It's okay, buddy.
现在你安全了
You're safe now.
- 嗨，拉娜 - 嘿
-Hi, Lana. -Hey.
- 赖恩要来告别了 - 你要去哪？
-Ryan would like to say goodbye. -Where are you going?
边缘城市
Edge City.
克罗伊的调查在那儿找到了他姑姑 她今天下午就会来
Chloe's research turned up an aunt there. She's coming by this afternoon.
我要谢谢你给的关于斯凯的建议
I wanted to thank you for your advice on Skye.
你是对的，她偷钱柜里的钱
You were right. She was stealing from the till.
- 嘿 - 哇
-Hey. -Wow.
谢谢你
Thank you.
我觉得你让他这一年都心花怒放了
I think you made his year.
所以你恢复了吗？
So you recover yet?
不知道，但我肯定陷入爱河了
I don't know, but I'm definitely in love.
正好加入我的俱乐部吧
Join the club.
你没在整理行李吗？
Shouldn't you be packing?
我不回大都会了
I'm not going back to Metropolis.
拜托，莱克斯，自从我派你到这来 你都想回去啊…
Come on, Lex, that's all you wanted ever since I assigned you...
…你很善辩地提到这地方像“垃圾工厂”的
...to what you so eloquently refer to as the "crap factory."
我知道你为什么想要我回去
I know why you want me back.
我快把你逼疯了，是吗？
I'm driving you crazy, aren't I?
我没有在俱乐部通宵玩到早上六点 没有被警察逮捕，我生活一切井然有序
I'm not clubbing till 6:00 a.m., not getting arrested. I'm on track.
这就是让你害怕的
That's what scares you.
你想让我回去好监视我
You want me back where you can keep an eye on me.
你想错了，莱克斯
You're making a mistake, Lex.
你知道那些你很喜欢谈论的君王 真正害怕的是什么吗？
You know what those emperors you're so fond of talking about were really afraid of?
是他们的儿子会成功…
That their sons would become successful...
…统帅他们自己的军队通往罗马
...and return to Rome at the head of their own army.
你认为你在斯摩维尔能找到未来
You think you can find your future in Smallville.
我才是你的未来
I'm your future.
来帮我，莱克斯，来大都会帮我
Join me, Lex. Join me in Metropolis.
你等我说这些等了多久？
How long have you been waiting to hear me say those words?
我已经等你说点别的事情更久了
I've waited to hear other things from you for a lot longer.
- 我准备好的时候会回大都会的 - 当你统帅大军的时候？
-I'll return to Metropolis when I'm ready. -At the head of an army?
我们会很想念你的，赖恩
We're really going to miss you, Ryan.
边缘城市很冷 所以我收拾了一些克拉克的旧夹克…
It gets cold in Edge City, so I packed some of Clark's old jackets...
- …你长大后可以穿的 - 谢谢，肯特夫人
-...something for you to grow into. -Thanks, Mrs. Kent.
任何时候你想回这里我们都欢迎你
You're welcome around here any time you want.
我知道你在担心，但是不用
I know what you're worried about, but don't be.
我会保守克拉克的秘密
I'll keep Clark's secret.
我知道在这个世上要隐藏好自己该怎样
I know what it's like to have to hide who you are from the world.
她来了
There she is.
你会好好的吧？
You sure you're gonna be all right?
她是个好人
She's a nice person.
只是和我一样紧张罢了
She's just as nervous as I am.
你确定不想知道拉娜对你是怎样的感觉？
Are you sure you don't want to know how Lana feels about you?
我更愿意自己去寻找答案
I prefer to find out on my own.
克拉克…
Clark....
小心点莱克斯
Be careful of Lex.
我知道你喜欢他…
I know you like him...
…但他内心有许多不可告人的黑暗
...but there's a lot of darkness he keeps from the world.
我从他脑中读出来了
I've seen it in his head.
我愿意相信人们最好的一面
I like to believe in people's best.
我要给你些东西
I want you to have something.
- 我不能拿这些 - 我不再需要去幻想他了
-I can't take those. -I don't need them anymore.
我有你
I have you.
再见
See you.
拜拜
Bye.
好了
Okay.